Guide to the Herbert Matter Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2: Correspondence, 3 linear ft.
  - Subseries 2.01: Incoming
    - Subsubseries 2.01.24: Published Works
      - Published Works [Folder 2 of 8].ND, Typed and handwritten letters (Box 258, Folder 2)
      - Published Works [Folder 3 of 8].ND, Typed letters (Box 258, Folder 3)
      - Published Works [Folder 4 of 8].ND, Typed letters (Box 258, Folder 4)
      - Published Works [Folder 5 of 8].ND, Typed letters (Box 258, Folder 5)
      - Published Works [Folder 6 of 8].ND, Typed and handwritten letters (Box 258, Folder 6)
      - Published Works [Folder 7 of 8].ND, Typed and handwritten letters (Box 258, Folder 7)
      - Published Works [Folder 8 of 8].ND, Typed letters (Box 258, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2.02: Outgoing
    - Subsubseries 2.02.01: Family
      - Family.ND, Handwritten letter: cable (Box 259, Folder 4)
    - Subsubseries 2.02.02: Business
      - Business.ND, Handwritten letter: cable (Box 259, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2.03: Houston First Savings
    - Houston First Savings.ND, Handwritten and typed letters: invoices (Box 259, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2.04: Knoll Associates
    - Knoll Associates.ND, Handwritten and typed letters: invoices (Box 259, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2.05: Mura Dehn Dance Studio
    - Mura Dehn Dance Studio [Folder 1 of 3].ND, Handwritten and typed letters: invoices (Box 260, Folder 1)
    - Mura Dehn Dance Studio [Folder 2 of 3].ND, Handwritten and typed letters: invoices (Box 260, Folder 2)
    - Mura Dehn Dance Studio [Folder 3 of 3].ND, Handwritten letters and notes (Box 260, Folder 3)
- Series 3: Artifacts, 23 linear ft.
  This series contains material such as oversized prints, posters, objects (scale models), photographic film boxes (empty), 16mm and 35mm film reels and canisters (empty), Matter's 8"x10" format studio camera, contact printer and damaged, though viewable black and white negatives (4"x5" and 8"x10"). The most fragile items in the collection are the predominately black and white glass plate negatives (mostly 4"x5" and some 8"x10"). The glass plates are among Matter's earliest work and includes several images of his photography from Paris, ca. 1928-1932. Also notable are the original (4"x5") glass plates for his studies with "electrostatic discharge emulsion."
  - Subseries 3.01: Oversized Prints
    - Light drawing; 1943.1943, print is approximately 37 1/2"x48" and mounted on board: Requires conservation. Not boxed. (Oversize 311)
      Included in 1943 exhibition of Matter's first one-man show of photography at Pierre Matisse Gallery in New York City.
    - Montage print.1943, print is 37 1/2"x48": mounted on board: color image with cabbage: requires conservation: not boxed. (Oversize 312)
    - Boston and Maine Railroad (BandM) logo., mounted and framed approximately 48"x48". Not boxed. (Oversize 313)
      Included in 1962 exhibition of Matter's photography and graphic design, American Institute of Graphic Arts (AIGA) in New York City.
    - New Haven Railroad (NHRR) logo b/w., mounted and framed approximately 44"x46". Not boxed. (Oversize 314)
    - New Haven Railroad (NHRR) logo color., mounted and framed approximately 44"x46". Not boxed. (Oversize 315)
    - Giacometti print., print is 24"x68" and mounted on wood board. Not boxed. (Oversize 316)
    - Boston and Maine Railroad timetable logo.ND, 48"x48" mounted on board. Not boxed. (Oversize 317)
    - Ski posters (4)., Mounted on aluminum. Approximately 26"x40": Requires extensive conservation. Not boxed. (Oversize 318)
    - Giacometti print - Kunsthalle basel poster announcement "25, June - 28, August"., Mounted on board with wood braces. Not boxed. (Oversize 319)
    - Matter Teahouse logo, mounted and framed approximately 50"x74".Not boxed. (Oversize 320)
      Included in 1962 exhibition of Matter's photography and graphic design, American Institute of Graphic Arts (AIGA), in New York City.
    - Atomic Head logo., mounted and framed approximately 50"x74". Not boxed. (Oversize 321)
    - Florida National Bank (FNB) logo., mounted and framed approximately 50"x74". Not boxed. (Oversize 322)
    - Cummins Engine Company logo., mounted and framed approximately 50"x74". Not boxed. (Oversize 323)
    - Abstract form.ND, 28 1/4"x24 1/2" mounted on board. Needs extensive conservation. (Othertype 422)
    - Eastern Indian Dancer; Pravina.ND, 22 1/2"x25 1/2" mounted on board. Needs extensive conservation. (Othertype 422)
  - Subseries 3.02: Objects (Models)
    - Cummins Engine Company; Scale Model for trade show exhibition; Harry Weese architect.1959, Wood: paper: fabric: and plastic scale model construction: Part of model is a regular cube 6"x6"x6" with top side open. Model is fragile and several pieces have come apart. Model requires conservation. (Carton 303)
      Scale model requires conservation.
    - Cummins Engine Company; Scale Model for trade show exhibition; Harry Weese architect.1959, Wood and paper scale model construction: Base of model is 14"x 14". Model is fragile and several pieces have come apart. Model requires conservation. (Carton 304)
    - Unidentified client; chemical symbols including documentation.ND, Small mounted boards. (Othertype 440, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3.03: Photographic Film Boxes
    - "Mrs. Grosman"; Grosman, Tatyana [Box 1 of 2]., Empty cardboard film boxes (Carton 332)
      Related to Universal Limited Art Editions.
    - "Mrs. Grosman"; Grosman, Tatyana [Box 2 of 2]., Empty cardboard film boxes (Carton 333)
    - Empty cardboard film boxes; Includes 35mm slide boxes., Empty cardboard film boxes. Includes empty 35mm slide boxes (Carton 334)
    - Empty cardboard film boxes ca. 1940s.1940s ca., Empty cardboard boxes: discoloration and tears along seams. (Carton 406)
    - Various empty film boxes.ND, Various empty film boxes. (Carton 423)
  - Subseries 3.04: Film Reels and Cannisters (16mm and 35mm)
    - Empty film reels and cannisters [Box 1 of 4]., Rusty metal films cannisters. (Carton 328)
    - Empty film reels and cannisters [Box 2 of 4]., Rusty metal films cannisters. (Carton 329)
    - Empty film reels and cannisters [Box 3 of 4]., Rusty metal films cannisters. (Carton 330)
    - Empty film reels and cannisters [Box 4 of 4]., Rusty metal films cannisters. (Carton 331)
    - Empty metal film reels. (Carton 335)
  - Subseries 3.05: Photographic Equipment
    - Photographic equipment; 16mm film viewer circa 1950s; Made by Camera Equipment; 1600 Broadway; New York City. [There is no box. Item will be tagged instead], Film viewer equipment: 13"x18"x10.5" with 7" screen: Requires cleaning. (Carton 327)
  - Subseries 3.06: Color Vinyl Display Panels
    - Displays for use with a lightbox; Cummins trade show; Siam - Indian dancer (damaged); Pravina; Indian dancer (damaged); foil crumpled (damaged); Chinese puppet (damaged); abstract light drawing (damaged); opaque backs.ND, Color vinyl panels: Siam - Indian dancer (water or heat damage on top left corner causing warping): Indian dancer (damaged): foil crumpled (warped corner and surface due to water or heat): Chinese puppet (water or heat damage on top left edge and corner causing warping): abstract light drawing (warped due to heat or water along edge) (Othertype 408)
  - Subseries 3.07: Yale
    - Farewell card to Herbert Matter signed by students; Haver, Helen;Haver, Erwin; Heuser [sic], Bernard; Hofmann, Armin; Hofmann," "Paula; Ives, Norman; Ives, John; Johnson, Peter and Lynda;Johnson, Cathy; Knigh [sic?], Ted; Marmaras [sic?], Jack; Maum [sic?], Edward; Miller, Ruth; Morris, Robert; Morton, Margarit; Pontes,Cormilda; Preier, Barbara; Pullman, Esther; Purvis, Elston S., Reea [sic?], Julie Curtis; Schripper, Steven; Strong, Tom; Thompson," "Bradbury; Thompson, Deen; Thorton [sic?], Susan; Tory [sic?]," "Andrea; Watson, Jim A.; Wondinka [sic], William; Zander, Janet; Zander, M.; unidentified last name, Hope and Abbey.1976 ca., 36105116158473; Blue heavy hardboard portfolio case with flip top lid that is attached to bottom of case: 29"x32 1/5": Cover of lid contains large "M" on white sheet 28 3/4"x 23 1/2" (Othertype 410)
  - Subseries 3.08: Glass Plate Negatives
    - Abstract forms.ND, b/w 5"x7": 8"x10". (Box 445)
      Includes photocopies of images in negative format.
    - Folded fabric; Solarized folded fabric; Original prints separated and placed with abstract prints.ND, b/w 8"x10". (Box 446)
    - Young girl; eyes closed; hands behind head (Trudi Hess); unidentified man with round glasses, looking down; Matter's room/studio (Paris); unidentified man, collared shirt; suit, sweater (looking off camera); unidentified man, collared shirt, suit, sweater (looking off camera) - chipped negative; unidentified woman lying down, hand on shoulder; montage photograms of woman; upright book; female statue; miniaturized man; unidentified man with binoculars looking off camera; possible view from Matter's Paris studio; female sculpture knees and up.ND, b/w 4"x5". (Box 447)
    - Unidentified woman lying down hair in face (Trudi Hess); cracked across surface; unidentified woman lying down finger in mouth; unidentified woman lying down looking 3/4 view profile; unidentified girl with fur collared jacket; "Hyspa" Bern; 1931 graphic design; chipping to emulsion surface; Matter painting 1930 framed; embracing figures; gypsy girl (lying down; torn sweater and polka dot sleeves); unidentified home; framed windows and walls; positive film transparency; Far East dancer with hand applied red paint to plate; girl with fur collared jacket; broken plate.ND, b/w 4"x5". (Box 448)
    - House and Garden; Plus abstracts.ND, b/w 4"x5". (Box 449)
    - Electrostatic discharge on emulsion.ND, b/w 4"x5". (Box 450)
    - Abstract forms.ND, b/w 4"x5": 5"x7". (Box 451)
    - Waterfall-like image.ND, b/w 4"x5": broken and cracked. (Box 452)
    - Boy and girl posed; close ups of wood flooring (graphic design client); symbols on clay; pebbles; Knoll furniture; blue office chair; Back view; Broken.ND, color 8"x10": "14 1/2"x11": back view plate is broken. (Box 453)
    - Montage with transparencies cut and placed together; Two women fashion models.ND, color 8"x10". (Box 454)
  - Subseries 3.09: Camera
    - Camera with red bellows with case; [There is no box for the camera; camera will be tagged instead].1950 ca., 8"x10" large format camera with red bellows with case: Including (14) 8"x10" film holders: (1) ground glass (broken): (2) shutter cable releases: assorted gelatin filters: 3" square. (Othertype 466)
  - Subseries 3.10: Posters
    - New York Studio School (NYSS); 1967-1968., 24 3/4"x14 1/2": mulitple copies. (Othertype 442)
    - New York Studio School (NYSS); Opening September 20, 1965.1965 ca., 23"x30": multiple copies. (Othertype 442)
    - Knoll Furniture; printed covers for (Knoll): Textiles Jan 15, 1966.1966 ca., 20"x26": Uncut: Printed on both sides:Two sets to a sheet. (Othertype 442)
    - Photograph; Brazil; Sculpture.ND, 20"x26": Extensive damage. (Othertype 442)
    - Photograph; Navajo boy dancer; Santa Fe, New Mexico.1942 ca., b/w 20"x25 1/2": Damaged. (Othertype 442)
    - Photograph; Pravina; Eastern Indian Dancer; Two images.ND, b/w 24 1/2"x28 1/2": damaged. (Othertype 442)
    - Kunsthaus, Zurich; Photo-Galerie 8; September bis 26; November 1978; Herbert Matter exhibition.1978 ca., 35 1/2"x50 1/2". (Othertype 444)
  - Subseries 3.11: Contact Printer
    - Contact printer light box; "Professional Contact Printer Model 2"; [There is no box for the printer; printer will be tagged instead].1950 ca., Contact printer light box: "Professional Contact Printer Model 2". (Othertype 467)
  - Subseries 3.12: Damaged Negatives
    - Unidentified exhibition model; abstract honey; unidentified male bust; unidentified model close up (Muriel); Box 1 of 2].ND, b/w 4"x5": 8"x10" negatives: warped with creases and folds. (Othertype 424)
    - Early Knoll; 1948 ca; including Knoll showroom; de Cordoba; ice skates; 19th century interior kitchen; globe map; nude (not Mercedes Matter) in studio; fashion; abstract discs; Corning Glass Pavilion; Guston, Philip; Colonial Williamsburg; rubber cement abstract; orchid; flowers; woman's hands; bust with covered eye; Box 2 of 2]ND, b/w 4"x5": 8"x10" negatives: warped with creases and folds. (Box 425)
- Series 4: Graphic Design Projects, 71.5 linear ft.
  This series contains approximately half of the Matter collection. It includes both commercial photograph and graphic design work. Completed projects and production materials such as prints, cut and paste, and layout work involved in the development of commercial work. Clients include Knoll Associates (furniture), various museums, New Haven Railroad, Boston-Maine Railroad, Florida National Bank, Swiss National Tourist Office (Ski Posters), Container Corporation of America, Conde Nast publications, arts and architecture magazine and others in addition to unidentified client work. Negatives, transparencies, published examples of work, source material, and working prints. Material is black and white (prints, negatives, transparencies) and color (transparencies, and a small number of color negatives). Graphic designs (layout, paste up, logotypes, sketches) are mostly color, some black and white. Series includes extensive material related to Knoll Associates (1946 to 1966), and the Museum of Modern Art, New York, the Guggenheim, New York and the Museum of Fine Arts, Houston. Collection includes prints and negatives associated with the publication; Masters of modern art; edited by Alfred H. Barr, Jr. for the Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.). New York, Distributed by Simon and Schuster 1954, and Modern sculpture from the Joseph H. Hirshhorn collection. [Commentary: H.H. Arnason], New York, 1962. Catalog of "Exhibition '62/6, October 3, 1962-January 6, 1963." for the Guggenheim. Additionally, Matter's mural designs for the Seagram building and the Grosse Pointe (Michigan) Library.
  - Subseries 4.01: Knoll Associates
    - Subsubseries 4.01.01: Photographic Prints
      - Knoll Accessories; bowls; cups; desk calenders; vase., b/w prints (Othertype 282)
      - Cartree (Knoll dog)., b/w prints (Othertype 282)
      - Knoll Factory Interiors; Exteriors., b/w prints (Othertype 282)
      - Knoll; Hans and Florence (Casual and formal); Includes Alexander Pundy Matter with the Knolls., b/w prints (Othertype 282)
      - Florence Knoll and Knoll [Folder 1 of 6]; Cabinets; tables; sofas; chairs; settee., b/w prints (Othertype 283)
      - Florence Knoll and Knoll [Folder 2 of 6]; Drawers; tables; desks; chairs., b/w prints (Othertype 283)
      - Florence Knoll and Knoll [Folder 3 of 6]; Drawers; tables; desks; chairs., b/w prints (Othertype 283)
      - Florence Knoll and Knoll [Folder 4 of 6]; Drawers; tables; desks; chairs; cabinets; sofas., b/w prints (Othertype 283)
      - Florence Knoll and Knoll [Folder 5 of 6]; Desks; drawers; cabinets; sofas; chairs; tables., b/w prints (Othertype 283)
      - Florence Knoll and Knoll [Folder 6 of 6]; Desks; drawers; cabinets; sofas; chairs; tables; settee., b/w prints (Othertype 283)
      - Boeri, Cini., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Dupre, Andre., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Furniture showroom and related., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Jeanneret, Pierre., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Nakashima, George., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Noguchi, Isamu., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Olson, Odelberg., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Risom, Jens., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Sorenson, Abel., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Tapiovaara, Ilmari., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
      - Theodore Waddell's Light Sticks., b/w prints (Othertype 285)
        Includes brochure for Light Sticks.
        Waddell, Theodore
      - Pollock, Charles., b/w prints (Othertype 286)
      - Saarinen, Eero [Folder 1 of 4]; Table; chair, b/w prints (Othertype 287)
      - Saarinen, Eero [Folder 2 of 4]; Table; chair; chair frame, b/w prints (Othertype 287)
      - Saarinen, Eero [Folder 3 of 4]; Tables; chairs; desks, b/w prints (Othertype 287)
      - Saarinen, Eero [Folder 4 of 4]; Tables; chairs, b/w prints (Othertype 287)
      - Takahama, Kazuhide, b/w prints (Othertype 287)
      - Library furniture [Folder 1 of 2]., b/w prints (Othertype 288)
      - Library furniture [Folder 2 of 2]., b/w prints (Othertype 288)
      - Pettit, Don., b/w prints (Othertype 288)
      - Schultz, Richard [Folder 1 of 3]., b/w prints (Othertype 288)
      - Schultz, Richard [Folder 2 of 3]., b/w prints (Othertype 288)
      - Schultz, Richard [Folder 3 of 3]., b/w prints (Othertype 288)
      - Knoll textile and fabrics., b/w prints (Othertype 289)
      - Office furniture., b/w prints (Othertype 290)
      - Unidentified lighting., b/w prints (Othertype 290)
      - Zapf, Otto., b/w prints (Othertype 290)
      - Albinson, Don., b/w prints (Othertype 291)
      - Breuer, Marcel., b/w prints (Othertype 291)
      - Butler, Lewis., b/w prints (Othertype 291)
      - Defucio, Robert., b/w prints (Othertype 291)
      - Eldon, Jim., b/w prints (Othertype 291)
      - Bertoia, Harry; chairs; tables [Folder 1 of 2]., b/w prints: photostat (Othertype 292)
      - Bertoia, Harry; chairs; tables; Knoll factory interiors [Folder 2 of 2]., b/w prints: photostat (Othertype 292)
      - Matta, Roberto Sebastian., b/w prints (Othertype 292)
      - Stephens, Bill [Folder 1 of 3]., b/w prints (Othertype 292)
      - Stephens, Bill [Folder 2 of 3]., b/w prints (Othertype 292)
      - Stephens, Bill [Folder 3 of 3]., b/w prints (Othertype 292)
      - Wegner, Hans., b/w prints (Othertype 292)
      - Mangiorotti, Angelo., b/w prints (Othertype 293)
      - Mies van der Rohe, Ludwig; sofas; tables; chairs., b/w prints (Othertype 293)
      - Mies van der Rohe, Ludwig; portrait., b/w prints (Othertype 293)
        series of 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 b/w prints on 8x10 sheet
      - Platner, Warren., b/w prints (Othertype 293)
      - Scarpa, Tobia; Knoll photographic prints; working prints; contact prints; finished prints., b/w prints (Othertype 293)
      - Cafiero, Vincent., b/w prints (Othertype 297)
      - Hannah, Bruce; Morrison, Andrew., b/w prints (Othertype 297)
      - Ferrari-Hardoy, Jorge., b/w prints (Othertype 298)
      - Knoll textiles; fabrics; Includes Jack Lenore Larsen, Nate Horwitt, and Abraham Zusteg., b/w prints (Othertype 298)
      - Pearson, Max., b/w prints (Othertype 298)
      - Seagram building., b/w prints (Othertype 298)
      - Rassmussen, Jorgen., b/w prints (Othertype 298)
    - Subsubseries 4.01.02: Printed Material
      - Knoll catalogs and brochures on chairs; benches; tables; cabinets [Box 1 of 2]., spiral bound: binder: and brochures (Box 280)
      - Knoll catalogs and brochures on chairs; benches; tables; cabinets library furniture [Box 2 of 2]., spiral bound: brochures (Othertype 281)
      - Knoll printed material finished tearsheets [Folder 1 of 3]., color and b/w sheets (Othertype 294)
      - Knoll printed material finished tearsheets [Folder 2 of 3]., color and b/w sheets (Othertype 294)
      - Knoll printed material finished tearsheets [Folder 3 of 3]., color and b/w sheets (Othertype 294)
      - Knoll printed material finished Ephemera clippings., b/w clippings (Othertype 294)
      - Knoll fabric swatches; Knoll advertising layouts; drawings; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats; transparencies., swatches: layouts: poster boards: transparencies (Othertype 295)
      - Bertoia, Harry; poster boards; layouts; color and b/w negatives; chairs; layouts; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats., b/w photostats: 8x10 color and b/w negatives: poster boards (Othertype 296)
      - Albinson; Don; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats; b/w prints; poster board., b/w photostats: b/w prints: poster board (Othertype 296)
      - Mies van der Rohe, Ludwig; poster boards; ink drawings; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats., b/w photostats: poster boards: ink drawings: b/w prints (Othertype 296)
      - Pettit, Don; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats; poster boards., b/w photostats: poster boards: b/w prints (Othertype 296)
      - Pollock, Charles; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats; poster boards., b/w photostats: poster boards: b/w prints (Othertype 296)
      - Saarinen, Eero; b/w prints; pencil drawings; poster boards; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats., b/w photostats: poster boards: pencil and ink drawings on tracing paper: b/w prints (Othertype 296)
      - Drawing sketches; pencil and ink drawings; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats., b/w photostats: b/w prints: pencil and ink drawings on tracing paper; b/w prints (Othertype 296)
      - Schultz, Richard; Knoll printed material layouts; photostats; poster boards., b/w photostats: poster boards: b/w prints (Othertype 296)
      - Knoll printed material finished tearsheets (oversized)., b/w and color sheets (Othertype 296)
      - Knoll printed material layouts; photostats; assorted., b/w photostats: b/w prints (Othertype 296)
  - Subseries 4.02: Seagram
    - Seagram. (Othertype 204, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.03: History of Writing
    - Images of completed mural., b/w prints. (Othertype 179, Folder 1)
    - Sketches; notes., Paper sketches: notebook. (Othertype 179, Folder 2)
    - Explanation of symbols., Typewritten: handwritten notes. (Othertype 179, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence., Typewritten: handwritten letters. (Othertype 179, Folder 4)
    - Project material., Photostats: source material: b/w 4x5 contact prints. (Othertype 180, Folder 4)
  - Subseries4.04: Museums
    - Subsubseries 4.04.01: Museum of Modern Art
      - Invitation for special preview of MOMA reopening., White cardstock with pink and black ink. (Box 170, Folder 5)
      - Guston, Philip; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 8x10 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 7)
        Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.)
      - Monroe Wheeler furniture; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 4x5 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 21)
        Wheeler, Monroe;; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.)
      - Peter McGray architectural model; Niemeyer; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4: 4x5 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 22)
      - Alvar Aalto furniture; Bruno Mathsson chair; Includes portrait of Alvar and Aino Aalto; ["box" 1 of 2]., b/w 2 1/4: 8x10 contact prints. (Box 181, Folder 23)
        Aalto, Alvar; Aalto, Aino; Mathsson, Bruno
      - van der Rohe, Mies; Masters of Modern Art book., b/w 8x10: stamped on back Photograph by Herbert Matter. (Box 181, Folder 27)
      - Bauhaus; Masters of Modern Art book., b/w 8x10: stamped on back Photograph by Herbert Matter. (Box 181, Folder 28)
      - Museum of Modern Art. (Othertype 200, Folder 3)
      - Nouveau Guimard desk; Masters of Museum of Modern Art book.ND, b/w 8x10 print:stamped on back Photograph by Herbert Matter: written in pencil on back 1647-0-3. (Othertype 200, Folder 4)
      - Glass and porcelain objects; Masters of Museum of Modern Art book.ND, b/w 8x10 print:stamped on back Photograph by Herbert Matter. (Othertype 200, Folder 5)
      - Brancusi, Constantin; Masters of Museum of Modern Art book.ND, b/w 8x10 print:stamped on back Photograph by Herbert Matter. (Othertype 200, Folder 6)
    - Subsubseries 4.04.02: Guggenheim
      - Catalogs; Brochures; Pamphlets [1 of 3]., Color and b/w booklets and posters: 10x5: 6 3/4x10: 8 1/2x11: 11x17. (Box 170, Folder 1)
        Booklets: Elements of Modern Painting, Inagural Selection, Modern Masters, European Drawings, Frederick Kiesler: Environmental Sculpture, Fernand Leger: Five Themes and Variations, One Hundred Paintings from the David C. Thompson Collection, Abstract Expressionists Imagists, William Baziotes.
        Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum
      - Catalogs; Brochures; Pamphlets [2 of 3]., Color and b/w booklets and posters: 10x5: 6 3/4x10: 8 1/2x11: 11x17. (Box 170, Folder 2)